Today, we are going to do Puja to Shiva, Shri Shiva.
今天我們將要做濕婆神崇拜
As you know Shri Shiva is the reflection of Sadashiva within us.
你也知道，濕婆神是至高濕婆神 在我們內在的反映
I have already told about the reflection.
我已經告訴你有關這個反映
Sadashiva is the God Almighty,
至高濕婆神是大能的神
the One who sees the play of Adi Shakti.
祂看著太初之母的戲劇
But He is the Father
祂是天父
who is watching each one of His Creation or Her Creation.
觀看著祂或她所創造的每一件作品
His support to Adi Shakti is entirely, fully strengthening.
祂毫無保留 盡心盡力的支持太初之母
There’s no doubt in His mind about the capability of the Adi Shakti.
祂對太初之母的能力是毫無疑問的
But when He finds that, in the play of Adi Shakti,
當祂發現在太初之母的戲劇裡
the people of the world as such, try to disturb Her,
例如這個世界的人想騷擾她
or spoil Her work then He gets into His wrathful mood
或想破壞她的工作 祂就會處於震怒的情緒
and He destroys all such people and maybe He destroys the whole world.
摧毀所有這些人 或許祂會摧毀整個世界
On one side He is wrathful no doubt,
一方面，毫無疑問 祂是極之憤怒
on the other side He's the ocean of compassion and joy.
另一方面，祂是慈悲和喜樂的海洋
That's why when He's reflected within us
這就是為何當祂反映在我們內在
we get our Self-realization. We get the light of our spirit
我們就得到自覺 得到靈之光
and we get into the ocean of joy.
並進入喜樂的海洋
Also He is the ocean of knowledge,
祂也是知識的海洋
So, those who get self-realized get the knowledge of the Divine,
所以得到自覺的人 亦得到精微的上天知識
which is very subtle, permeating into every atom and molecule,
這知識滲入每粒原子 每粒分子
the power of this knowledge is there.
知識的力量都存在那裡
His style is such that in His compassion
祂的風格是這樣的 在祂的慈悲裡
He forgives even very cruel rakshasas
若最殘暴的惡魔肯順服於祂
if they dedicate themselves to Him,
祂甚至會原諒他們
because His compassion has no limits. And sometimes
因為祂的慈悲是無限的
But it is just to create a drama, a event.
這只為創造一齣戲劇，一件事件
Unless and until there is some drama people won’t understand.
除非有這些戲劇上演 人們是不會明白
We had to have Ramayana, we had to have Mahabharata,
我們要有羅摩衍那(Ramayana) 我們要有摩訶婆羅多(Mahabharata)
we had to have Christ being crucified, we had to have Mohammed being tortured.
我們要有被釘上十字架的基督 我們要有受折磨的穆罕默德
All that drama was there because without events people don’t remember.
所有這些戲劇都必須上演 沒有一些事件，人們是不會記著
So in the spiritual life of human beings they have seen lots of dramas
所以在人類的靈性生命裡 他們已看過在濕婆神的福佑
between the blessings of Shiva and the powers of the Adi Shakti.
和太初之母的力量之間的多齣戲劇
As the time has moved today in the history of spirituality
隨著時間的推移 今天在靈性歷史
a great discovery has been made. That people can get their realization
有一個了不起的發現
Now we should know what is this Realization we have got.
現在，我們要知道 我們得到的自覺是什麽
What does that mean and what is the culminating point.
它代表什麽 什麽是終點
First of all, I have to tell you the mind about which we speak
首先，我要告訴你 我們按思維說出來的說話
and depend upon is a myth. There’s nothing like mind.
我們依靠的思維都是虛假的 沒什麽東西像思維
Brain is reality, not the mind.
腦袋是真實的，思維卻不是
Mind is created by us reacting to outside,
思維是我們對外在作出反應 而創造出來
either we react to conditionings or to our ego.
我們一是對制約 一是對自我有反應
Thus this mind is created like bubbles on the ocean of reality,
因此，思維就像實相的海洋裡的泡沬 被創造出來
but that’s not reality. With this mind whatever we decide
但它不是實相。這個思維 不管我們決定什麽
we know is very limited, illusive and sometimes shocking.
我們知道都是很有限的，亦只是幻象 有時也很令人震驚
The mind always moves in a linear direction,
思維常常以直線移動
and because there's no reality in it, it recoils and boomerangs.
因為它沒有實相，它反彈 再回到原位
Thus all the enterprises, all the projections so far we have done,
因此所有企業 到目前為止我們所有的投射
it seems, come back to us. Whatever they discover
都反彈回我們身上 不管他們發現了什麽
comes back to us as a big destructive power or a very big shock.
都以很大的毀滅力量 或很大的震撼回到我們身上
So one has to decide what to do, how to be out of this trap of our mind.
因此我們要決定該怎麽辦 怎樣可以離開我們思維的陷阱
Kundalini is the solution. When She’s awakened, She takes you -
靈量就是答案 當靈量被喚醒
with that awakening She takes you beyond your mind.
透過這份喚醒 她帶你超越你的思維
The first thing is to go beyond your mind. With mind you’ll do many things
首先是超越你的思維 透過思維，你做很多事情
but it will not be satisfying, it will be not a solution, it will not help you.
但都不會得到滿足感 它不是答案，幫不了你
And when we start depending too much on our mind
當我們過份依賴思維
we develop all kinds of physical, mental, emotional problem.
就會產生各種肉身上 精神上和情緒上的問題
Now the latest is the stress. Stress, and this stress has no solution they say,
現在最新的是精神壓力 他們說精神壓力是沒法解決的
but in Sahaja Yoga we find the solution by crossing over this mind.
但在霎哈嘉瑜伽 我們發現超越這個思維就是解決辦法
It’s like a barrier for our advancement. So, when you get your realization,
它就像我們進步的障礙 當你得到自覺
you must understand that your Kundalini has taken your attention beyond the mind.
你必須明白 你的靈量帶你的注意力超越思維
Now, this reaction to outside has come because we human beings have
我們對外在有反應 是因為我們人類的腦袋像棱鏡
a prism-like brain, or we can say a prism-like skull,
或我們可以說像棱鏡的顱骨
and when the energy passes into it, I have explained it in My books,
當能量進入它 我在我的書有解釋過
it goes into bifurcations or you can say refractions
它就進入分叉 或你可以說折射
by which our attention goes out and we react.
我們的注意力因此往外走 我們有反應
If we react too much then these bubbles create a very horrible mind
若我們反應過度 這些泡沫就會創造很可怕的思緒
which can lead to any kind of thing. It justifies itself, it pampers your ego.
可以帶我們進入各種狀況 它自我辯解，縱容你的自我
The ego and the conditioning that creates this mind
創造這個思緒的制約和自我
start using and - this mind, for the purpose of their fulfillment,
就會運用這個思維完成實現
of their all the accumulation of ideas and thoughts
他們積累下來的主意和想法
which has no backing, which has no reality with it.
這些主意想法是沒有根據 沒有實相的
It’s like we make the computer, ultimately we become slaves of the computer.
就像我們製造電腦 最終變成電腦的奴隸
We make the watches ourselves and then we become slaves of the watches.
我們製造手錶 卻變成手錶的奴隸
That’s how it dominates human beings and when a person
它就是這樣控制人類
who has a very strong mind decides to destroy, like Hitler did,
當有很強意志的人決定去摧毀 像希特勒
with some idea he can go on destroying which has a very far-fetched effect
當他有一些想法 他就會不停毀滅
on our culture, on our spirituality.
那是對我們的文化 我們靈性有很深遠的影響
Now the first step is to become thoughtlessly aware,
現在第一步是要變得無思無慮的覺醒
where you cross your mind. You go above your mind.
你要超越思維 高於思維
Mind cannot affect you. This is the first stage as we call is thoughtless awareness.
思維再不能影響你，這是第一階段 就是我們稱為無思無慮的覺醒狀態
Second one is where, you see, start seeing the working of this Paramachaitanya,
第二步是你開始看到這生命能量
of this all-pervading Power and you start becoming aware
這無所不在的力量的運作
that there is lot of truth in what Mataji says.
你開始知道瑪塔吉說了很多實相真相
That there is this power, which works out many things.
這力量成就很多事情
It works miraculously so many things for you.
為你成就很多奇妙的事情
It gives you blessings, it guides you, it helps you, in so many ways it helps you.
它給你福佑，指引你 多方面幫助你，它幫助你
It gives you good health, good wealth and also a very good society
給你健康，給你財富 也給你好的社會
of very beautiful people in the collective.
在集體裡漂亮的人
All that you can see clearly is happening here.
你能清楚的看到這種情況在這裡發生著
Now this happening of
要到達無思無慮的
achieving thoughtless awareness is very simple and easy,
覺醒狀態是既簡單又容易
but to maintain at that point is difficult. We still react and we think.
但要保持這個狀態卻是很困難 我們仍有反應，仍然在想
Anything you see you react. To get to that point in thoughtless awareness
任何你看到的事物，你都有反應 要到達無思無慮的覺醒
is first, to change your attention.
首先要改變你的注意力
Now for example, once we were climbing a very high mountain to see one temple
就如我們有一次登上很高的山 去看名為Palitana的廟宇
And we were really tired because we had to climb - I don't know how many steps
我們都真的很疲累 因為我們不停的往上走 我也不知道走上了多少樓梯
and when we went up we were tired and there was a little canopy
當我們到達，大家都很累 哪裡有個用很漂亮
made of beautiful marble carving, so we just laid down ourselves.
大理石雕刻而成的頂篷 我們在那裡躺下
They were very tired and they said, "What is this kind of a temple," they were grudging.
大家都很累，他們說︰ 「這是怎樣的廟宇？」他們在抱怨
While I looked up and I saw lots of beautiful elephants were carved.
而我向上望 看到頂篷雕了很多漂亮的大象
So I told My son-in-law, "Look at these elephants,
我告訴我女壻︰ 看看這些大象
they all have tails of different types."
他們有不同款式的尾巴
He said, "Mommy, we are all dying, how can You see the tails of elephants?"
他說︰「媽媽，我們都累死了 你還看大象的尾巴？」
But is just to divert their attention from that tiredness, I told them that,
我只是想把他們的注意力從疲累裡轉移 我告訴他們
why not see these tails of the elephant, which is very different.
為何不看看大象的尾巴 那是很不同的
So what happens that when you are putting your attention
什麽在發生 當你時刻都把你的注意力
so much to outside all the time,
放在外在的事物上
then you must first of all also divert your attention.
你必須先把注意力轉移
For example, you see these beautifully made things here.
例如，你看到這裡漂亮的東西
Your attention is something else, just try to enjoy the beauty of that.
你的注意力…只要享受它們的漂亮
See there are beautiful carpets here, just look at them without thinking,
看看，這裡有漂亮的地毯 只看著它們，不去想
because they don't belong to you so no headache, they belong to somebody else
因為它們不屬於你 所以不會令你頭痛，它們是別人的
is very good. Otherwise if it belongs to you, you'll will start thinking,
這很好，不然，若它是你的，你就會想
"Oh my God, I've spreading them here what will happen, they have to be insured”
天啊！我把它放在這裡，什麽會發生 我要為它們買份保險
or some sort of thing like that. That's common human reaction
或你會做類似的事情 這是一般人的反應
but if it doesn't belong to you, you can watch it nicely.
但若它不是你擁有的 你就可以好好欣賞它
Now you watch it and don't think, you'll be amazed
現在你看著它，什麽也沒有想
when you see the beauty that is put inside this.
當你看到它的漂亮 你會很驚訝
You'll see the artist who has put his joy, his exuberance into it
你會看到藝術家把他的喜樂 他的熱情放進地毯裡
and you'll be amazed after realization that this exuberance
你會很驚訝，在有自覺後 這份熱情也會充滿你
and this Kundalini will rise and you’ll become steady in your thoughtless awareness.
靈量昇起 你就能在 無思無慮的覺醒狀態下穩定下來
So whenever you look at anything, look at any beautiful thing,
每當你看到什麽 看到什麽漂亮的事物
even say today's election, just watch the man who is elected [John Howard].
即使如今天的選舉 只看被選中的那個人(John Howard)
Watching him itself gives him blessings, gives him better ideas.
只看著他，給他祝福 給他好的主意
You get also ideas which are coming from reality, which are there,
你也得到某些來自實相的主意 這些主意就在這裡
how to make this man a successful person or this country a successful democracy.
怎樣令他成為成功人士 或這個國家怎樣能成為成功的民主國家
All these things happen when your attention is diverted
所有這些事情的發生都是
from criticising, from reacting,
當你的注意力從批評 從有反應中轉移過來
just you watch, become the witness, try to witness everything.
你只是觀看，變成旁觀者 嘗試靜觀一切
It's not so very yet practiced,
但你仍未有實踐
so far I've seen, that whenever even we get our, achieve our realization
到目前為止 我看到即使我們得到自覺
we don't realize that we have to witness everything.
仍不知道我們要靜觀一切
When you start witnessing through your spirit, then you don't see
當你開始透過你的靈靜觀
We just pick up a person with very good points.
你只撿起別人的優點
So once you see that the witness state enlarges
一旦你看到自己的旁觀見証狀態擴大
and you start enjoying another person, you start enjoying everything that is there.
你開始享受別人，享受一切
Even a small blade of grass you can enjoy if you have that capacity.
若你有這份能耐 即使只是一小片葉，你也享受
In Japan Zen system started on these lines.
在日本，禪宗亦是按此線路開展
And he made - Viditama was the person who started it.
禪宗是菩提達摩開展的
He made a garden out of moss, different moss, very small, small.
他用苔蘚，不同的苔蘚 很細小的苔蘚造了一個花園
There were little, little flowers also. And hardly about five feet of the garden,
也放進一些小花朵 花園的面積還不到五呎
which looks like the shape of a question mark, you can say.
你可以說它的形狀像一個問號
You have to go on a lift and you reach that platform
你要坐升降機到達一個小山丘或
on top of a hill or a mountain where you see this.
一個山頂的平台 就看到這個花園
All little, little mosses are there
有很細小的苔蘚
and you see differently arranged a beautiful garden.
有不同的排列，很漂亮的花園
When you start seeing it your thought stops.
當你看到這個花園 你的思緒就會停止
Because such a marvelous thing, when you put attention to it,
因為它是那麽令人驚奇 當你放注意力在它
to its creation, your thoughts stop. So you must practice
它的受造物上，你的思緒就會停止 你必須練習一下
as to find out what stops your thoughts. What makes you the witness?
怎樣停止思緒 怎樣令自己成為旁觀者
Once you develop this habit you will station yourself nicely
一旦你養成這種習慣 就能好好的 在無思無慮的覺醒狀態裡駐足
in the thoughtless awareness. Then you start watching
那麽你就開始靜觀霎哈嘉瑜伽是
how Sahaja Yoga has helped you. How it has been blissful.
怎樣幫助你，怎樣對你是種極樂
What you have achieved through Sahaja Yoga.
透過霎哈嘉瑜伽你有什麽成就
You will be amazed if you just start watching it
若你開始靜觀它，你會感到驚訝
everywhere you'll be amazed how this Paramachaitanya acts.
你會驚嘆生命能量是怎樣在四周運作
Nowadays this Paramachaitanya has become active because of Krita Yuga.
現今，因為過渡期(Krita Yuga) 生命能量變得活躍
You can see from the way it is playing around with vibrations around Me,
你可以在四周圍繞著你生命能量裡 看到它是如何運作
you've seen so many photographs of Mine where these vibrations are there.
你看過我很多相片都有生命能量
Also you've seen the photographs of many Sahaja yogis sitting before Me,
你也看過很多坐在我前面的 霎哈嘉瑜伽士的相片
on their head My name is written down in Arabic language.
他們頭上都有 以阿拉伯文寫上的我的名字
You've seen so many ways by which you can find out
你從很多途徑都能看到和找出
that there is the play of the Divine.
上天的戲劇在上演
Now the mind will still try to say some things, don't listen, just watch.
現在思維仍會說一些話 不要聽，只要看
The effect of Sahaja Yoga you should watch, on yourself, on your body.
你要自己去看霎哈嘉瑜伽的效果 在你身上的效果
Don't think about it, but watch it and you'll be amazed how you have changed.
不要想，只要看 你會驚嘆於自己的改變
To be very frank when I come to Australia every year
坦白說，當我每年到澳洲
sometimes I can't even recognize you. You look much younger,
我有時甚至認不出你們 你們看來更年青
much better, much happier and I don't recognize who are these people.
更好，更快樂 我認不出你們是誰
It is this witness state which takes you to another realm
就是這種旁觀見証狀態 把你們帶到另一個我們稱呼為
which we call as doubtless awareness.
無疑惑的覺醒狀態的領域
At that state you can become so empowered that you can give realization to others.
在這個狀態 你變得如此獲授權給人自覺
You can give realization to others. You can give
你可以給自覺別人
I'm, you see, when I'm watching I'm absorbing the heat, that's My trouble.
我是，你看，當我在看 我在吸收那些熱力，這是我的煩惱
So your whole state, spiritual state,
因此你整個狀態，靈性的狀態
becomes so much blissful. You become so powerful.
變得那麽極樂滿足 你變得那麽有力量
You become so compassionate and so loving, so balanced,
那麽慈悲，那麽有愛心，那麽平衡
completely cleansed with all the destructive ideas you have,
你曾經有的毀滅性的、抑鬱的想法 都完全被潔淨
Like recently I heard that Germans and Austrians are now going to Israel
就如最近我聽到 德國人和奧地利人要到以色列
because they think Jews were killed by their forefathers.
因為他們想 他們的祖先殺死很多猶太人
And there's a big center now start[ed] in Israel. Just imagine
現在有一個很大的中心在以色列被建立 只想像
how these people once reach that state, go to countries single-handed,
這些人一旦到達這個狀態 單人匹馬的到這些國家
they have done so much. Same in Turkey,
他們做了很多事 土耳其也一樣
same in places, which are very tremendously remote in South Africa.
同樣，南非是極之遙遠的地方
Because from inside they become completely confident
因為他們內在變得完全有自信
in thoughtless awareness as well as doubtlessly aware.
在無思無慮的覺醒狀態 亦在無疑惑的覺醒狀態
But now once you start growing by meditative attention,
現在，一旦你在入靜的注意力下 開始成長
what happens that your attention becomes enlightened.
你的注意力就變得開悟
Now the job is to motivate your attention.
現在的工作是激發你的注意力
It's not just to enjoy, but to motivate it, to put it to problems.
不單只去享受 而是激發它，令它產生問題
Now supposing you have some problem on a national basis
例如你有一些國家層面的問題
you all can put your attention to that and things will work out.
你們可以把注意力放在這些問題上 事情就會得到解決
Because you are the channel of this all-pervading Power
因為你是這個想為你創造
which is trying to create a new world for you, new human beings.
新世界，新人類的全能力量的管道
And this evolution can take place very fast if you all decide
進化可以很快，若你們全都決定︰
that whatever we have now within ourselves we should motivate it,
不管我們內在擁有什麽 我們都要激發它
we should direct it and put this attention to some use.
引導它，把這份注意力 放在一些有用的事情上
It should not be wasted. Whatever wealth we have it should not be wasted.
不要浪費 不管我們有什麽資源，都不要浪費
Now this main question today, which I'm going to tell you about
現在我要告訴你今天的主要問題
that what is God's realization. First is the Self-realization
什麽是神的自覺？首先是自覺
and there are many ambitious people who want to become God's-realized.
有很多有野心的人想有神的自覺
First and foremost thing we should know that human beings cannot become God.
最重要的是我們要先知道 人類不能成為神
It's not the becoming of it.
就是不能變成神
You have not become also in a way spirit because the spirit is emitting through you,
你也不能變成，某程度上，變成靈 因為靈是透過你散發
using you, giving you, looking after you.
它運用你，給予你，照顧你
If you become the spirit there won't be any body left, nothing will be left.
若你變成靈 就沒有任何肉身剩下來，沒什麽剩下
So with this body intact, your spirit is acting through this body,
因此當這個肉身保持完整 靈是透過這個肉身運作
is giving you all the light.
給予你所有的光
But one cannot become God Almighty; this one has to understand very clearly.
我們不能成為大能的神 你們要清楚明白這一點
But what is God's realization is to know about God.
神的自覺就是知道神
You see, to know about God means to know how His powers are working.
你要明白 知道神即是知道祂的力量怎樣在運作
How He controls by becoming part and parcel of God Almighty.
知道祂怎樣控制一切 變成大能的神的一部分
Like My finger doesn't know about My brain, but it acts according to My brain.
就如我的手指不知道我的腦袋 但它卻按我腦袋的指示行事
The finger cannot become the brain,
手指不能成為腦袋
but it has to act absolutely according to My brain
但它卻絶對按腦袋的指示而行
because it is so connected, it is so one.
因為它們是連上的 是一體的
Here when you have the God's realization then you know about the brain,
這裡，當你有神的自覺 你就知道腦袋
you know about God, you know about His powers, you know everything about Him.
知道神，知道祂的力量 知道祂的一切
As far as I'm concerned it's a difficult task for you, because I'm a Mahamaya.
以我所知，對你這是困難的任務 因為我是摩訶摩耶
It's very difficult for you to know each and everything about Me.
你要知道有關我的每一件事情 是非常困難的
I'm quite a elusive person as you know that well,
我是頗為虛幻的人 你知道得很清楚
and whatever I do or whatever I achieve, it is just for you to see and understand
不管我做了什麽，成就了什麽 只為讓你看到和明白
that after all this is Adi Shakti and She can do all these things.
畢竟是太初之母 她能做所有這些事情
You can also do all the things but you cannot become Me.
你也能做所有事情 但你不能成為我
But you have to know, to know through love, through devotion, through prayers
你要知道，透過愛 透過虔敬，透過禱告
to know the God's Powers is the way you are God-realized.
去知道神的力量 是你是神的自覺的途徑
Then you can control the nature, you can control everything,
你就能控制大自然，控制萬事萬物
if you have that knowledge within you about God.
若你內在擁有神的知識
For that a complete humility is needed that you cannot become God,
為此完全謙卑是需要的 你不能成為神
cannot become God Almighty. You cannot become the deities
不能成為大能的神 不能成為神祇
but definitely you can become God-realized. Means God acts through you,
但你肯定能成為神的自覺 即是神透過你行動
uses you as His power, as His channel and that you know, that you know
運用你作為祂的力量 你成為祂的管道，你就知道
what He's doing to you, what He's telling, what His vision is
祂對你做了什麽 告訴你什麽，祂有什麽遠景
and what is the information. The connection is like that.
什麽消息，就像這種聯繫
Many people in Sahaja Yoga have been benefited, I know.
我知道，很多人在霎哈嘉瑜伽裡得益
But they don't know how they have been benefited. What has worked it out?
但他們卻不知道自己怎樣得益 什麽已經成就
How it has worked it out. What connection of theirs has helped them?
怎樣成就到 他們的什麽聯繫在幫助他們
Once you do that, you know that, clearly how things are working out,
一旦你這樣做，你清楚的知道 事情是怎樣成就
with what power you have achieved it, then it's a God's realization.
透過什麽力量你成就它 那就是神的自覺
Such people become extremely powerful in the sense
這類人變得極之有力量 某程度上
that they can control so many things.
他們能控制很多事物
There have been many saints of that kind
有很多這類的聖人
but sometimes they fell from even that and they developed their ego.
但有時他們甚至在這層次下跌 因為他們發展了自我
They didn't have their own humility that they should have,
沒有那份應有的謙卑
that devotion, that dedication, that surrendering.
那份虔敬，那份奉獻 那份順服委身
They fell down and you see them, I've seen some of them that they become
他們下跌。你看他們 我見過他們一些人
They think they have achieved it with great difficulties
他們以為自己是克服極大的困難 才得到這些成就
and why should they give it to others. Such people are not going to rise very higher.
那麽為何要給其他人 這類人不會昇得很高
But you people who have got your realization and who are humble,
但你們卻有自覺，很謙卑
who know that out of humility only you are going to achieve your surrendering.
知道只有謙卑才能達致順服委身
Islam means surrender. Mohammed Sahib has talked about Islam,
Islam 的意思是順服 穆罕默德曾談及” Islam”
meaning, "you surrender." If you cannot surrender you can never know God.
即「你的順服委身」 若你不能順服，就永遠不會知道神
Is clearly said that, "Unless and until you know yourself
祂清楚的說︰除非你知道真我
you will not know about God."
否則你不會知道神
So as Sahajis you have to know all the little, little things,
作為霎哈嘉瑜伽士 你要知道所有小事
all the big things, and all the great visions,
亦要知道所有大事 所有偉大的遠景
that you can do it because of the grace of God, because His blessings,
你能這樣是因為透過神的恩典 神的福佑
because of His love for you, that you have entered into the Kingdom of God.
神對你的愛 你已進入神的國度
I may say you have entered, I may say you have achieved that state,
我可以說你已進入 可以說你已經到達這個狀態
I may say that. But still you are not there.
我可以這樣說，但你仍未到達
It's like if I tell somebody, "Now you are in Australia."
就如我告訴某人︰你現在在澳洲
He's not in Australia, but I can say you are in Australia.
他不是在澳洲 我卻可以說︰你在澳洲
So he believes, "I am in Australia", that's not the way.
他因此相信︰我是在澳洲  不是這樣
You have to be in Australia, then you have to know about Australia.
你必須身處澳洲 你要知道澳洲
You have to know what sort of climate it is, what sort of things it is.
要知道哪裡的氣候如何 有什麽事物
I find the also the parents here have to talk to their children.
我發現這裡的父母 也要與他們的孩子談談
There's not much rapport of the parents with the children.
父母與孩子的關係不大融洽
They are being properly looked after in the school and they want to do a lot
學校已經好好照顧孩子 很多事情他們都想做
but the parents also must get involved when the children come here
但父母必須也參與 當孩子來這裡
to see that they develop proper discipline, proper sense.
要看到他們發展適當的紀律 適當的判斷力
Not to get attached to them, to ruin them. If you get attached then you'll ruin them.
不要依附著他們而摧毀他們 若你黏貼著他們，就會摧毀他們
One of the qualities of Shiva is complete detachment
濕婆神其中一種品質是毫不執著
and that is what you have to develop, is to become completely detached.
你就是要發展這種品質 變得完全不執著
Detachment doesn't mean that you neglect anything.
不執著不是說你忽視一切
I've explained to you many-a-times that like the sap in the tree rises,
我已多次向你解釋 就如樹木的汁液向上升
goes to different, various places and then evaporates
到樹的不同部位 然後蒸發掉
or it goes back to Mother Earth. In the same way your detachment should be.
或回到大地之母 你的不執著也一樣
If you get attached because it's your son or if you get attached
若你的執著是因為他是你的兒子
or certain class then you are still limited.
某個階層 那麽你仍有限制
All these limitations have to be dropped, if you have to cross over.
若你想超越 所有這些限制都必須抛掉
And these limitations create such a big load that whatever I may try,
這些限制創造了很大的包袱 不管我怎樣嘗試
whatever you may try you cannot stay in thoughtless awareness.
不管你怎樣嘗試 都不能保持在無思無慮的覺醒狀態
That's a very beautiful state in which all of you should be there.
這是很漂亮的覺醒狀態 你們全部人都要在這個狀態
In that you are not dominating nor you are compromising.
在此你既不專横亦不妥協
You stand on your own legs and you know for definite
你獨立自主，你肯定知道
that you are not swayed away by any idea or any domination
自己不會因任何想法 任何控制而搖擺不定
or any subjection of yours by anyone. So you become a completely a free bird,
亦不會屈服於任何人 你因此變得絶對自由
absolutely a free bird, and then it becomes your job to achieve your flight.
完全自由 你的任務是達致你的飛躍
One flight is up to the thoughtless awareness.
一飛就到達無思無慮的覺醒狀態
The second one is up to the doubtless awareness
再飛就到達無疑惑的覺醒狀態
and the third one is to God's realization.
接著飛就是神的自覺
I've seen people who are very close to Me also don't understand.
我曾見過與我很親近的人都不理解
They behave in such a manner as if now they've become gods.
他們的言行就像他們現在已經變成神
So egoistical they are that I am amazed at them. Then they have to leave Sahaja Yoga.
那麽自大，我對他們也感到很驚嘆 他們必須離開霎哈嘉瑜伽
So you see, even if I praise you too much, if I say anything too much,
所以你要明白 即使我對你有過多的讚美，若我說得過份
you shouldn't get pampered. It's a testing ground.
你也不應受縱容 這是試驗場
Or otherwise also if I tell you that,
又或與此不同，若我告訴你︰
"This is not good, you should improve on this", you shouldn't mind,
這樣不好，你要改善糾正 你不應介意
because I have to do it, that's My job. And your job is to listen to Me.
因為我必須這樣做 這是我的任務，你的任務就是聆聽我
Because I have nothing to gain from you. I do not ask for anything.
因為我在你身上沒什麽得益 我不會要求什麽
What I want is you all should get all My powers. You may not become what I am,
我只想你們全都能取得我的力量 你或許不能成為我
agreed, but please try to get all the powers that I have.
這一點我同意 但請嘗試取得我擁有的所有力量
Which is not a difficult thing.
這不是難事
This is what is God's realization. That's what is to know Shiva and Sadashiva.
這就是神的自覺 也就是要知道濕婆神和至高濕婆神
Through the Shiva you know Sadashiva. You see the reflection
透過濕婆神，你認識至高濕婆神 你看到反映
and from reflection you know who is the original.
從反映裡，你知道誰是本源
From the reflection you learn. Thus you reach that state where you think
你從反映裡學習 因此你到達某種狀態，在這狀態
you are now definitely settled in the Kingdom of God
你想你現在肯定已經安頓在神的國度裡
and that you can see God, you can feel God,
你能看見神，感覺神
you can understand God.
明白神
And you can love God.
亦能愛神
So may God bless you.
願神祝福你們